# VINCENT R. SÁNCHEZ

Javascript Engineer

# Summary

I am a web developer with a love for building web apps and a passion for using Javascript to bring ideas to life. With more than two years of experience, I have come to find that, despite its flaws, Javascript is a beautiful and powerful language bolstered by a truly awesome and inclusive community of programmers who share the same regard for its capabilities. I am particularly fond of React.js as it is a paradigm shift with a lot of promise. The focus on separation of components rather than an arbitrary separation of concerns, combined with the expressive power of JSX provide an intuitive way to conceptualize user interface architecture, all while simply leveraging the power of Javascript to manage state and data flow within in application.

# Web Development Skills

- Comprehensive experience coding client- and server-side Javascript.
- Proclivity for assessing code to recognize prime refactor opportunities.
- Understanding of the important role software unit testing plays in the development of clean, modular code.
- Seasoned in use of version control (Git) for code management.
- Well-versed in use of browser debugging tools.
- Familiar with integrating web apps and NoSQL data stores.
- Knowledgeable of current trends and issues in web development.
- Excellent communication and writing skills.

#### Experience

# National Necrotizing Fasciitis Foundation, Remote

2014 - 2015

Implemented top to bottom overhaul of non-profit organization's website.

Upgraded look and feel of webpage by incorporating responsive design principles where none had existed.

Greatly enhanced user experience for company's mobile audience. Established and maintained Twitter account for foundation.

U.S. Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, New York, NY 2012

Maintained FOIA IMS database using CRUD functionality to handle data entries on pending charges.

Various Non-technical roles, New York, NY

2006 - 2014

Restaurant industry, volunteer work and internships.

## Education

John Jay College of Criminal Justice New York, NY

2005, 2009-2013

BA, Political Science, magna cum laude

GPA: 3.79, GPA in Major: 3.88

Senior Thesis: Twitter Interaction Among Members of the 113<sup>th</sup> Congress

Reintroduction to programming (R)

# Key Skills

#### **KNOWLEDGE OF**

Node.js

Linux / Ubuntu

Express

Bootstrap

• React.js

jQuery

MongoDB

AJAX

• Git

HTML5 / CSS3

#### **KEY COMPENTENCIES**

- An unrelenting drive to write code powering web apps with rich user experiences.
- The boundless curiosity needed to keep up with the break-neck rate of change in the tools and techniques of modern web development.
- The desire to continually improve skills by tackling formidable yet rewarding problems.
- The capacity to thrive both independently and as part of a collaborative team effort.

#### **RECENT PROJECTS / OPEN SOURCE CONTRIBUTIONS**

# ShopScraper

Single-page web application using Node.js to scrape product data from local grocery stores for increased personal shopping savings. UI built with React.

#### Tweet Cloud

Web app that uses Twitter API to search tweets, and arranges them into an interactive three-dimensional sphere. Used Bootstrap, AJAX, jQuery, PHP.

# NNFF Official Webpage

Took early 2000's style UI/UX and implemented a complete modern restoration using React, Express and Bootstrap.

# **JsTagSphere**

Identified source of bug that prevented proper rendering of content when doctype declared, making cool software impractical for use in HTML5. Fix allowed me to incorporate the code into the Tweet Cloud.

#### **HOBBIES AND INTERESTS**

I have played guitar for 14 years and I love to listen to music, especially hip hop, punk and indie rock. In my free time I enjoy cooking or traveling around the city to try new food.

# COMMUNITY PRESENCE

GitHub (tdbts)
Stack Overflow (tdbts)
Twitter (VRSanchez8717)

# **CONTACT DETAILS**

Vincent R. Sánchez 138-62A 68<sup>th</sup> Drive Flushing, NY 11367

T: 347-255-3115 E: VinnySanchez87@gmail.com